Sierra Club, Atlantic Chapter; Records apap130
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Conservation Committees and Regional Groups, 1968-1996; 2; 1.6 cubic ft.
  - Regional Groups, 1968-1996; 2.2; 1.3 cubic ft.
    - Regional Groups, Iroquois Group, Newsletters, 1972-1994 (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 21)
    - Regional Groups, Long Island Group, Correspondence, 1969-1995; 2 folders (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 22-23)
    - Regional Groups, Long Island Group, By-laws, Meetings, Newsletters, 1969-1995 (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 24)
    - Regional Groups, Lower Hudson/Westchester - Putnam Group, 1973-1984; 1994 (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 25)
    - Regional Groups, Mid-Hudson Group, By-laws, Membership, 1969-1990 (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 26)
    - Regional Groups, Mid-Hudson Group, Meetings, 1969-1990 (Box 1 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 27)
    - Regional Groups, Mid-Hudson Group, Correspondence, 1969-1990; 3 folders (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 1-3)
    - Regional Groups, Mid-Hudson Group, Newsletters, 1969-1990 (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 4)
    - Regional Groups, New York City Group, 1966-1968; 1973; 1982-1984 (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 5)
    - Regional Groups, New York City Group, 1988-1990; 2 folders (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 6-7)
    - Regional Groups, New York City Group, 1993; 1996 (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 8)
    - Regional Groups, Niagara Group, Correspondence (Folder 1 of 3), 1968-1990 (Box 2 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 9)
    - Regional Groups, Niagara Group, Correspondence (Folder 2-3 of 3), 1968-1990; 2 folders (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 1-2)
    - Regional Groups, Ramapo-Catskill Group, 1982-1988 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 3)
    - Regional Groups, Rochester Group, Correspondence, 1970-1990; 2 folders (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 4-5)
    - Regional Groups, Rochester Group, By-laws, Finances, Membership, 1970-1990 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 6)
    - Regional Groups, Rochester Group, Meetings, 1970-1990 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 7)
    - Regional Groups, Rochester Group, Newsletters, 1970-1990 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 8)
    - Regional Groups, Standards, 1984 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 9)
    - Regional Groups, Susquehanna Group, 1982-1990; 1996 (Box 3 (2-Conservation Committees and Regional ), Folder 10)
- Political Activity, 1983-1998; 3; 3.47 cubic ft.
  This series documents the Atlantic Chapter's various activities in the political process at the state and national levels. Included here are materials relating to its efforts to influence the 1988, 1990, 1992, 1993, 1994, 1996, and 1998 elections, such as endorsements and voter guides. The 1990, 1992, and 1994 elections are the most extensively documented. Other political activities the Atlantic Chapter engaged in include lobbying the New York State Legislature, tracking national political events (such as the Republican takeover of Congress in 1994), contributing to the revision of New York City's charter in 1989, and general grassroots activities. Also included are Atlantic Chapter documents relating to election law compliance and an electoral activity handbook for Sierra Club activists. There is also documentation of the offices, agencies, and initiatives of New York State government, including materials regarding Governors Mario Cuomo and George Pataki, the Legislature, the Department of Environmental Conservation, regulatory changes undertaken by Governor Pataki, and the State Environmental Quality Review Act (SEQRA).
  - Activists and Volunteers, 1989-1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 1)
  - Affiliation with Other Organizations, ca. 1990 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 2)
  - Binghamton Meeting and Lobby Day, 1994; 2 folders (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 3-4)
  - Change NY, ca. 1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 5)
  - Citizen Action, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 6)
  - Citizen Suits/SLAPP, 1971-1972; 1991-1992 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 7)
  - Civil Suits, 1993 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 8)
  - Community Organization Boards, Undated (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 9)
  - Congress of the United States, New York House Delegation and Others, ca. 1984-1986; 1991-1997 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 10)
  - Congress of the United States, Vote Charts, 1993-1996; 2 folders (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 11-12)
  - Congressional District Coordinator, 1991 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 13)
  - Conservation Committees Meeting, 1993 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 14)
  - Conservation Conference, 1995 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 15)
  - Corruption Allegations, 1997 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 16)
  - Croes, K. and J. Stouffer, "Building Our Grassroot Legislative Power", 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 17)
  - Education, 1968; 1974; 1977; Undated (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 18)
  - Election, 1988 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 19)
  - Election, 1990 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 20)
  - Election, Endorsements, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 21)
  - Election, General, 1992; 2 folders (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 22-23)
  - Election, Legislative Races, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 24)
  - Election, Political Program Publications, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 25)
  - Election, Presidential, 1992 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 26)
  - Election, 1993 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 27)
  - Election, Attorney General of New York, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 28)
  - Election, Congressional Races, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 29)
  - Election, Endorsements, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 30)
  - Election, Legislative Races, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 31)
  - Election, Political Committee Mailings, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 32)
  - Election, Political Program Publications, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 33)
  - Election, Poll, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 34)
  - Election, Post-Election Analysis, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 35)
  - Election, 1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 36)
  - Election, 1998 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 37)
  - Election Action Bulletin, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 38)
  - Election Campaign Tips, 1982; 1991 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 39)
  - Election Law Compliance, 1993; 1995 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 40)
  - Election Politics Handbook, 1984; 1988 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 41)
  - Electoral Training Materials, 1991; Undated (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 42)
  - Endorsements by Other Organizations, 1997 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 43)
  - Environmental Business Association of New York State, Inc., 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 44)
  - Environmental Justice, 1992; 1994 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 45)
  - Environmental Public Education Campaign, 1997 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 46)
  - Form Letters to Politicians, ca. 1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 47)
  - Grants, 1994-1996 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 48)
  - Grassroots Effectiveness Program (GREP), 1988-1990 (Box 1 (3-Political Activity), Folder 49)
  - Grassroots Information System Membership, ca. 1996 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 1)
  - Great Lakes Environmental Scorecard, 1994 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 2)
  - Legislative Races Questionnaire, Undated (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 3)
  - Legislative Report for Connect!, 1994 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 4)
  - Legislative Report for Sierra Atlantic, 1994 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 5)
  - Litigation Procedures, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 6)
  - Litigation Settlements, 1985 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 7)
  - Lobbying, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 8)
  - Lobbying, 1991 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 9)
  - Lobbying, 1993 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 10)
  - Lobbying, 1994; 3 folders (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 11-13)
  - Lobbying, Undated (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 14)
  - Lobbying, Earth Day Lobby Day, 1995 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 15)
  - Lobbying, Earth Day Lobby Day, 1996 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 16)
  - Lobbying, Earth Day Lobby Day, 1998 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 17)
  - Lobbying, Earth Day Lobby Day, Undated (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 18)
  - National Political Committee, 1992 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 19)
  - New York City Charter Revision, 1989; 3 folders (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 20-22)
  - New York State, Attorney General, 1993-1996 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 23)
  - New York State, Board of Elections, 1994 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 24)
  - New York State, Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 25)
  - New York State, Budget, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 26-27)
  - New York State, Conservation Fund, Undated (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 28)
  - New York State, Constitutional Convention, 1997 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 29)
  - New York State, Department of Economic Development, ca. 1987-1994 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 30)
  - New York State, Department of Environmental Conservation, 1972; 1982-1984 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 31)
  - New York State, Department of Environmental Conservation, 1992; 1994-1996 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 32)
  - New York State, Department of Health Center for Environmental Health, 1989 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 33)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 34)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1991 (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 35)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1992; 2 folders (Box 2 (3-Political Activity), Folder 36-37)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1993 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 1)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1993; 2 folders (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 2-3)
  - New York State, Environmental Trust Fund, 1995 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 4)
  - New York State, Governor, Cuomo, Mario, 1983-1994 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 5)
  - New York State, Governor, Pataki, George, 1994-1997 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 6)
  - New York State, Legislature, 1991-1993 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 7)
  - New York State, Legislature, 1994-1997 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 8)
  - New York State, New York Power Authority, 1994 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 9)
  - New York State, Public Service Commission, 1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 10)
  - New York State: Regulatory Reform, Business Council, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 11)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Campaign Finance Reform, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 12)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Conservative, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 13)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Cost-Benefit Analysis/ Risk Assessment, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 14)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Enforcement, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 15)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, General, 1994-1996; 4 folders (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 16-19)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, General Permits, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 20)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, National Events, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 21)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, NYSDEC Memos, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 22)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, NYS Dept. of Health, 1994-1996 (Box 3 (3-Political Activity), Folder 23)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Press Coverage, 1994-1996; 2 folders (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 1-2)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Reports, 1994-1996 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 3)
  - New York State, Regulatory Reform, Senate Hearing, 1994-1996 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 4)
  - New York State, State Environmental Quality Review Act (SEQAA), 1982 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 5)
  - New York State, State Environmental Quality Review Act (SEQAA), 1994; 4 folders (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 6-9)
  - News Clippings, 1995 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 10)
  - Nonprofit Organizations, Undated (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 11)
  - Northeast Regional Office War on the Environment Planning Workbook, 1996; 2 folders (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 12-13)
  - Political Analysis, 1995-1996 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 14)
  - Political Committee, ca. 1989 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 15)
  - Political Committee, 1995 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 16)
  - Political Education, Committee on (SCCOPE), 1984 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 17)
  - Political Education, Committee on (SCCOPE), 1985-1986 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 18)
  - Political Education, Committee on (SCCOPE), 1988-1989 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1996; Undated (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 20)
  - Regional Planning Conservation Subcommittee, 1994 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 21)
  - Requests for Assistance, 1993 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 22)
  - Sierra Student Coalition, 1994 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 23)
  - State Environmental Policy Acts, ca. 1990 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 24)
  - Take the Money.And Run: How Money and Politics Mixed in the 104th Congress and the Environmental Consequences, 1997? (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 25)
  - Trial Lawyers for Public Justice, 1989 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 26)
  - United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1996 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 27)
  - Voter Guides, 1996 (Box 4 (3-Political Activity), Folder 28)
- Subject Files, 1967-1998; 4; 13.17 cubic ft.
  This series covers twenty-five subjects of interest to the Atlantic Chapter, most of which are divided into several secondary topics. The subjects are defined below.
  Adirondack Park: All materials relating to the Adirondack Mountains, particularly in regards to land use and economic development in the Park in the early 1990s.
  Air Quality: Items about atmospheric pollutants and their impact on the environment and public health.
  Catskill Forest Preserve: Materials relating to the Catskill Mountains.
  Communications and Media: Materials documenting efforts by the Sierra Club to communicate its message to the general public through film, radio, T-shirts, and calendars.
  Earth Day: Materials documenting the Sierra Club's celebration of Earth Day (April 22).
  Economics: Economic issues that affect the environment, such as free trade agreements and the labor movement.
  Electricity: Materials documenting the electric industry in New York State, traditional energy sources such as nuclear power, alternative sources of energy such as solar and wind power, and federal legislation of concern to the Sierra Club.
  Global Warming: Materials about human-induced changes to the world's climate.
  Hazardous Wastes: Industrial by-products that are a danger to the environment and public health, such as dioxin, polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs), and radioactive waste (particularly low-level radioactive waste), as well as efforts at cleaning/reducing such wastes, such as Superfund.
  Land Use: Materials about the various activities that take place on (mainly) public lands, both economic (gas and oil drilling, logging, mining) and recreational (hunting, fishing, skiing), as well as efforts to control the development of land through easements and greenways.
  Local Government: Items regarding county and municipal governments in New York State.
  Miscellaneous: Items, usually hand-written, whose purpose or context is obscure.
  National Organization and Other Chapters: Materials produced by the Sierra Club's headquarters in San Francisco, and by other state chapters.
  Other Organizations: Documents produced by other environmental organizations.
  Pesticides: Materials about the environmental and health effects of pesticides, in particular about contamination of drinking water on Long Island.
  Press Coverage: News clippings about various topics at the state and national levels.
  Public Health: Materials about environmental risks to public health and organizations focusing on public health. Contains extensive documentation of the Comparative Risk Project.
  Recycling and Solid Waste: Materials about the control/disposal of trash through composting, incineration, etc., and about efforts at recycling items such as batteries, beverage containers, paper, and tires.
  Sewage and Sludge: Materials about the disposal of sludge (treated sewage) such as through application onto farmland ("biosolids") and assessment of the health risks this may pose.
  State Bonds: Bonds proposed or issued by New York State for the funding of environmental, transportation, and general projects.
  Storm King Mountain: Documents submitted to the Federal Power Commission by Consolidated Edison, the Sierra Club, and Scenic Hudson in 1967-1968 in regard to Consolidated Edison's plan to build a nuclear power plant at Storm King Mountain on the Hudson River.
  Takings (Eminent Domain): Materials about whether environmental regulations that limit economic activities on private property can ever be construed as eminent domain (i.e., a "taking" as defined by the US Constitution).
  Transportation: Materials about alternative forms of transportation such as electric or hydrogen cars and maglevs (magnetic trains), low emission vehicles, public transportation, the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act (ISTEA), New York and Ohio transportation policies, and the proposed Westway Highway in Manhattan.
  Water Quality and Use: Materials about water pollution, drinking water, coastal areas, dredging, rivers and streams, structures built on bodies of water, and industrial use of water.
  Wildlife and Habitat: Materials about the Sierra Club's efforts at preserving particular species (e.g., bald eagles, moose) and entire ecosystems/biomes such as the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, the Great Lakes, and the Great Northern Forest. Also includes information on state habitats such as the Albany Pine Bush, the Long Island Pine Barrens, and the Hudson River Estuary, and legislation such as the Endangered Species Act.
  - Adirondack Park, Activists, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Alliance, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Council, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Economic Development Corporation, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Fairness Coalition, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Park Agency, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Park Agency, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Planning Commission, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Adirondack Park, Centennial, 1992; 2 folders (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9-10)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Park Improvement Protection and Community Development Act (A.965 (Weprin et al)), 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Adirondack Park, Adirondack Pure Waters Act, 1995 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Adirondack Park, Adopt-A-Lake Program, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Adirondack Park, Article XIV Amendments, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Adirondack Park, Commission on the Adirondacks in the Twenty - First Century, 1980; 1986-1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Adirondack Park, Comparison of Governor's Draft Bill to Present Statute and Berle Commission Recommendations, ca. 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Adirondack Park, Constitutional Protection Conference, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Adirondack Park, Critique of Preservation Efforts, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Adirondack Park, Disabled Access, 1994-1997 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Adirondack Park, Environmental Trust Fund, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Adirondack Park, Finch, Pruyn and Co., 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Adirondack Park, Forest Taxes, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Adirondack Park, General, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Adirondack Park, Gore Mountain Ski Area, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Adirondack Park, Herbicides, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Adirondack Park, High Peaks Wilderness Area, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Adirondack Park, Hydropower, 1982 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Adirondack Park, Indian Lake Dam, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Adirondack Park, Land Acquisition, Leasing, and Sales, 1989-1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Adirondack Park, Legislative Proposal by Governor Cuomo, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Adirondack Park, Letters to the Editor, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Adirondack Park, Mining, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Adirondack Park, Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Adirondack Park, Mountain Bikes, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Adirondack Park, Navigable Waterways, 1991-1993; 1997; 2 folders (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36-37)
  - Adirondack Park, New York State Assembly Adirondack Working Group, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Adirondack Park, Northern Forest Campaign, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Adirondack Park, Olympic Regional Development Authority, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Adirondack Park, Pataki, George, 1994 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Adirondack Park, Piseco Airport, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Adirondack Park, Press Coverage, 1988-1990 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Adirondack Park, Press Coverage, 1991; 2 folders (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44-45)
  - Adirondack Park, Press Coverage, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Adirondack Park, Private Forest Lands, 1993 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Adirondack Park, Protection Campaign Platform, 1990 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Adirondack Park, Rally, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Adirondack Park, Residents, 1990 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Adirondack Park, Residents' Committee to Protect the Adirondacks, 1991; 1993 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Adirondack Park, Statewide Lobbying Groups, 1991 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Adirondack Park, Temporary Revocable Permits, 1996 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Adirondack Park, Transportation, 1993-1994 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Adirondack Park, Tupper Lake, 1994 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)